CLAIRE SMITH

Web developer

ABOUT

I am a self-taught web developer focused on crafting highly-responsive user experiences in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and WordPress. I am passionate about programming and always searching for ways to expand my knowledge. With my background in customer relations and journalism, I can bring a unique skill set to your team.

8464 N 1000 E LAFAYETTE, IN

CLAIRECSMITH001@GMAIL.COM



CLAIRESMITH11.GITHUB.IO

__

812-630-0032



RECENT PROJECTS

S'MORE TIME IN THE SMOKIES
Site: smoretimeinthesmokies.com

A custom-designed WordPress CMS template for a cabin rental company. I continually maintain and update the PHP code for the client.

DAZZLE JEWELRY STORE

Demo: dazzle-jewelry.herokuapp.com/ **Repo**: github.com/clairesmith11

A full-featured, scalable React singlepage application with a REST API and NoSql database. Utilizes the Paypal sandbox for payment demos.

PENNY'S ANIMAL SANCTUARY

Demo: pennyssanctuary.web.app/ **Repo**: github.com/clairesmith11

A demo app built with a React frontend and Node.js,/MongoDB back-end. Features a user-friendly, mobile responsive design.

COMMON CENT\$ BUDGET BUILDER

Code at: github.com/clairesmith11

A React/Redux SPA with a Firebase database for tracking monthly expenses. Calculates spending totals in various categories and compares data with previous months.

SKILLS

JAVASCRIPT HTML5 CSS & SASS RESPONSIVE DESIGN WORDPRESS REACT/REDUX NODE.JS/EXPRESS **BOOTSTRAP** MONGODB GIT ADOBE CREATIVE SUITE COMMUNICATIONS COPY WRITING CUSTOMER RELATIONS GRAPHIC DESIGN PROBLEM SOLVING ORGANIZATION

EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATIONS

B.A. IN JOURNALISM

Franklin College May 2011 Responsive Web Design Certificate FreeCodeCamp, June 2020 JavaScript Algorithms Certificate FreeCodeCamp, July 2020 Front End Libraries Certificate FreeCodeCamp, Nov 2020

WORK HISTORY

WEB DEVELOPER - SMORE TIME IN THE SMOKIES

Remote Nov 2020 - present

- Provide website and UX design using custom WordPress templates, CSS and HTML for a family member's business.
- Employ search engine optimization tactics to increase reach of targeted audience.
- · Implement website maintenance, content management, and updates on client requests.

CLIENT SERVICES ASSOCIATE - 1ST SOURCE BANK

Lafayette, IN July 2015 - present

- Provide superior customer service, helping our branch earn 98% or higher client satisfaction results for 5 consecutive years.
- Manage daily operations, including updating CRM databases and auditing for compliance with federal regulations.
- · Open accounts and investments and recommend products to customers based on their unique needs.

REPORTER/WRITER - DUBOIS COUNTY HERALD

Jasper, IN May 2011 - May 2015

- · Wrote daily stories in collaboration with fellow staff writers, photographers, and editors.
- Communicated with our 8,500 subscribers through superior reporting, written content, photographs, charts, graphs, and social media posts.